John McTeague

☑ john@mcteague.co.uk | ♠ http://github.com/johnmcteague ♣ +447775732391 | ♠ Glasgow, Scotland

Summary

Technology leader with 18+ years experience currently focused on cloud enablement with the ability to establish partnerships across organizational boundaries, build high performing teams and deliver high quality product aligned to business objectives in challenging and complex environments.

Considered a strong technology and business partner who builds trust and leads by example to achieve goals, mentors and grows talent to build talented, sustainable teams and maintain a high standard of technical excellence both personally and within my teams.

Specialities

Public and Private Cloud, Hybrid cloud arechitecture, transformation of application portfolio to public and private clouds, Software Engineering, Risk Management, Team Building and Leadership

Cloud Foundry, Amazon Web Services, Terraform, Python, Java, Spring, TDD, Continuous Delivery, Azure, Google Cloud, Docker, Kubernetes, Serverless

Experience

Mar 2008 - Present

JP Morgan Chase, Glasgow, Scotland

Public Cloud Engineering Lead and Architect

Engineering lead and architect deliverying Public Cloud Enablement that provides critical networking, security and automation services enabling JPMorgan to leverage multiple cloud providers. Leading an engineering team across 3 regions and partnering with key stakeholders across the firms technology landscape I am accountable for design and delivery of multiple services that provide the foundations of all public cloud workloads.

Directly designed and contributed to the development of provisioning and automation services for building provider accounts with secure baselines, scalable networking and IAM controls integrated into firmwide tooling. Responsible for the end to end design, delivery and overall SDLC for all cloud services components reporting to senior management, stakeholders and architecture boards on progress and approach.

Spearheaded the adoption of Terraform as a standard to support the firms multicloud journey, identifying the platform as a key enabler and engaging with Hashicorp (Terraform vendor) on product roadmap, best practice and architecture to ensure a successful deployment.

Cloud Enablement

Focused on driving the vision and advantages of PaaS adoption to the wider application development organization.

As a Cloud Native evangalist, engaged with Line of Business development teams to redesign for cloud, constructing a Cloud Native Maturity model to aid CTO/Architects in the journey to cloud native and presented at internal conference and developer days to ensure the cloud native message is spread as widely as possible.

Developed in depth Cloud Native training course for new graduate technologists within JP Morgan and facilitated training to approx 150 students in EMEA.

PaaS Architect Responsible for research and evaluation for JP Morgan's platform as a service (PaaS) offering, engaging with leaders and innovators in the PaaS ecosystem, establishing of selection criteria and evaluating against company needs. Lead initial engineering efforts for deployment, engaging with infrastructure specialists to deploy Pivotal Cloud Foundry on Openstack for private cloud

deployment across multiple data centers.

Product Owner, Business Intelligence Platform Lead all aspects of product lifecycle for in-house Business Intelligence tool set developed from best of breed Open Source and commerical components (BIRT, Jasper, Aspose.Cells) that delivered multi-million dollar cost saves from ~200 deployments compared to commerical offerings. Lead small team of 4 for client engagement, development and support of product.

Dec 2003 - Mar 2008

Student Loans Company, Glasgow, Scotland

Held various roles progress from developer to architect level, building and designing Java based solutions for the processing of student finance applications and integrating with external 3rd parties for secure data sharing and processing.

Aug 2001 - Nov 2003

Prudential Assurance, Stirling, Scotland

Graduate role developing a mixture of COBOL74 and J2EE solutions to manage regulatory mandated reviews of mis-sold mortgage products.

Education

1997 - 2001

BSc Computer Science

Strathclyde University, Glasgow, Scotland.